The Tumultuous Journey
(アシュラ)あ～あ なんか兄さん
変わったなあ。
Elder Brother has changed…
厳しいだけじゃ みんな
気持が離れちゃう気がするけど。
If he's just strict all the time,
I feel like he's going to
alienate everyone.
(タイゾウ)おっ いたいた
探したよ アシュラ。
Oh, there you are!
I was looking for you, Ashura!
タイゾウ。
今日の修業は終わりか？
Taizo!
Are you done with training today?
まあね 少しくらいサボったって→
Well, since Elder Brother's
going to take over Ninshu,
忍宗は どうせ
兄さんが継ぐしさ 俺なんて…。
it doesn't matter if I slack off a bit…
ふ～ん そうか。
Hmm… I see.
Well, it's less pressure on me!
まあ 気楽でいいけど
で 何か用か？
So, what's up?
あ ああ
ちょっと頼みがあるんだ。
Oh, oh…
I need a favor.
え？
(タイゾウ)忍宗で チョイと→
Can you use Ninshu to knock down
a few trees around here?
このあたりの木を
倒してくれないか？
え？ どうして？
ああ。
Huh? Why?
Ah…well...
まあ なんつうか
ここに切り通しがあれば→
If we clear a path through here,
we'll have a shortcut to the fields.
畑までの近道になるしさ。
お袋も便利になるし
お前なら ちょろいだろ？
It will be easier on my mom…
…and it's no big deal for you, right?
ああ そういうことなら
任せろ。
Is that all? Leave it to me!
こんなもんでいいかな？
Will this do?
ああ助かったぜ。
Yeah, you've been a big help.
いや この程度なら
お安い御用だ。
This kind of thing is easy.
タイゾウ！ 兄さん！
これは どういうことです？
Taizo!
Elder Brother!
What is the meaning of this?
(インドラ)この男は罪を犯した。
This man has committed a crime.
樹木を伐採し
己の財とした。
He took down the trees, treating them
as if they were his property.
里のものは 里全員のもの。
What's in this village
belongs to everyone.
それが掟だ。
That is the law.
罪は お前にもあるぞ
アシュラ。
You are just as guilty, Ashura.
え？ 俺に？
Huh? Me too?
お人よしが過ぎるぞ。
You were gullible.
お前は この男に騙され
罪の片棒を担がされたのだ。
This man deceived you and made you
an accomplice to his crime.
切り通しって
あれウソだったのか。
Was clearing a path, a lie?
母ちゃんが病気で
急いで薬が必要だったんだ。
My mom was sick and
needed medicine quickly.
すまない アシュラ
お前を巻き込んじまって。
I'm sorry I got you involved, Ashura.
どうして本当のことを？
病気なら忍宗で。
Why didn't you tell me the truth?
I could've used Ninshu if she was sick…
母ちゃんは
忍宗が嫌いなんだ。
Mom hates Ninshu.
She says this world
doesn't need Ninshu…
忍宗なんて
この世界にいらないって。
忍宗を信じようが
信じまいが 掟は掟だ。
Whether you believe in Ninshu or not,
a law is a law.
アシュラ
お前は何も知らなかった。
Ashura…
You didn't know anything about this.
今回だけ
お前の罪は不問に付す。
So just this once, you will be forgiven.
(ハゴロモ)インドラ だがこれは
やり過ぎではないのか？
Indra, perhaps you are taking this too far.
人は誰でも
間違いを犯す。
Everyone makes mistakes.
人を裁くことには
慎重でなければならない。
Judging people requires prudence.
わかっています父上。
I know that, Father.
ですが罪には 罰となる力を
毅然と示さねばなりません。
However, when a crime is committed,
proper punishment must be carried out.
それが 新たな罪の
抑止力となります。
Only then, will it act as a deterrent
against future crimes.
兄さん。
Elder Brother…
うう…。
アシュラ。
しっ 今逃がしてやる。
Ashura!
I'll let you out in a moment.
でも…。
But—!
いいんだ あとの責任は俺が取る。
It's okay.
I'll take full responsibility for this.
兄さん…。
Elder Brother!
アシュラ その男をどうするつもりだ？
Ashura, what do you think
you're doing with that man?
見逃してくれ 兄さん。
Please overlook this, Elder Brother!
こいつだって
悪気があったわけじゃないんだ。
He didn't do this
with malicious intent.
掟は掟だ。
The law is the law.
見せしめなら もう十分のはずだ。
Haven't you already made
an example of him?
それは
お前が決めることではない。
That's not for you to decide.
兄さんは俺がなんとかする。
今のうちに逃げろ。
I'll convince my brother somehow.
Go now.
すまない アシュラ。
Thanks, Ashura!
掟を破るなら…。
If you're going to break the law,
お前が代わりに罪を償え。
you can take the punishment instead.
やめてくれ 兄さん！
Stop, Elder Brother!
あっ！ くっ…。
アシュラ 掟は何のためにある？
Ashura, why do we have laws?
忍宗の力は何のためにある？
What is the purpose
of Ninshu's power?
自分で答えが出せぬなら
お前は私に従えばいいのだ。
If you can't answer
these questions yourself,
then you should obey me.
頭を冷やせ。
Calm yourself!
兄さん…。
Elder Brother…
SHIRO
父上。
Father!
今日は シロの命日です。
Today's the day Shiro died.
あのとき
シロと兄さんがいなかったら→
Back then, if Shiro and Elder Brother
weren't there, I would have died.
俺は死んでました。
俺は
みんなの力で生かされています。
SHIRO
I'm alive, thanks to everyone's strength.
お前は優しい心の持ち主よの。
You possess a gentle heart…
インドラとは真逆だ。
The complete opposite of Indra.
兄さんは優秀ですから。
Well, Elder Brother is extraordinary.
何でも一人でできるし
その力も持っています。
He can do anything by himself,
and he has the power to do so.
だからこそなのだ。
That is precisely why.
お前は インドラの目をどう思う？
What do you think of Indra's eyes?
どうって別に
写輪眼に威圧は感じますが。
What do I think?
Well, I do feel a bit intimidated
by them…
《やはり アシュラに
インドラの瞳力は通用せぬか》
As I thought…
Indra's Visual Prowess
would not work with Ashura…
どうかしたのですか？
Is something the matter?
インドラの目には わしにも読み取れぬ
不気味な冷徹さがある。
There's something ominous about
Indra's eyes that even I cannot fathom.
あの目を見ると思い出すのだ。
Looking into his eyes
makes me remember…
母上の目を。
my mother's eyes.
きっと兄さんには→
Perhaps Elder Brother can see things
that others cannot see?
他人には見えないものが
見えてるのではないでしょうか。
何が見えるというのだ？
Such as?
何か 高尚なものです。
忍宗の理想や未来とか…。
Something very advanced.
Like the ideal version of Ninshu,
or the future…
写輪眼のない俺には
わからないけど。
I don't know since I don't have
the Sharingan.
シロと一緒に俺を助けてくれた頃の
兄さんは優しかった。
But back then,
when he and Shiro saved me,
Elder Brother was very kind.
兄さんの本心は
あの頃と変わってないと→
I have faith that Elder Brother's heart
has not changed from those days.
俺は信じています。
俺も もっと修業を積んで→
I'll train harder and do my best
兄さんの力になれるよう
頑張ります。
to become someone that
Elder Brother can rely on.
＜ハゴロモ : わしは そのとき→
At that moment,
I felt I understood for the first time,
なぜ２人の息子を
天から授かったのか→
why heaven had blessed me
with two sons.
その意味を初めて知った気がした。
That was…
それは…＞
おい 聞いたか？
Hey, did you hear?
とうとう ハゴロモ様が
忍宗の後継者を選ぶらしいぞ。
Lord Hagoromo is finally
going to name his successor.
インドラ様とアシュラ様か。
どっちになるのかのぉ？
Master Indra or Master Ashura.
Which will it be?
そんなの 長男で忍宗の才に優れた
インドラ様に決まってるだろ。
There's no doubt, it's got to be
the elder one, Master Indra…
He excels in Ninshu!
これより
我が忍宗の後継者を決める。
And now, I am going to pick
my successor to Ninshu.
父上 何ですか？ これは。
Father, what is this?
わしが母上を封印したとき→
During the battle where
I sealed away my mother,
十尾の体の残骸が
世界のあちこちに散った。
parts of the Ten Tails were
scattered throughout the world.
大部分は わしたちが
旅したときに処理した。
We repaired most of the lands
during our journeys.
だが その巻物には
まだ処理しておらぬ→
But in that scroll, it is written
that there are two regions,
２つの地が書かれている。
which still need to be fixed.
Indra, Ashura…
インドラ アシュラ
お前たちはその地に向かい→
You will each go to these lands
そこで起きている問題を
解決するのだ。
and settle whatever problem
has occurred there.
その結果を見て どちらに
忍宗を任せるかを決める。
And after I see your results,
I will decide to whom I will
entrust Ninshu.
ハ ハゴロモ様。
なぜです 父上！
L-Lord Hagoromo…
Why, Father?!
なぜ こんなことを？
Why are you doing this?
俺に忍宗を継ぐべき才能が
ないことは…。
I don't have the skill to inherit Ninshu…
いえ 俺は
忍宗を継ぐ気などありません。
In fact, I have no desire
to inherit Ninshu.
I'm more than happy
just helping Elder Brother.
兄さんにつかえるだけで
十分です。
それは わしが決める。
That is for me to decide.
お前たちが世界に出て
何をするのか。
What will the two of you do
when you are out in the world?
すべては それを見極めてからだ。
When I see what comes out of that,
everything will fall into place.
どうして父上は あんなことを？
Why did Father decide to do this?
心配はいらない。
すぐに父上にもわかる。
Don't worry.
Father will come to understand quickly.
うん。
Uh-huh…
The younger one seems to have
matured into a kind and gentle soul.
(ガマ丸)弟のほうは 優しい気性の
持ち主になったようじゃの。
(ガマ丸)じゃが 写輪眼の力を
受け継いだのは 兄のほうか。
But the older one inherited the power
of the Sharingan, huh…
もしかすると あの弟は
兄のことを考え→
But out of consideration
for his older brother,
the younger one might
not return home.
里には戻らぬかもしれぬぞ。
そうなれば そのときだ。
I will deal with that
when the time comes.
そうまでして
何を試したいのじゃ？
What is it that you want to test?
試したいわけではない。
It's not a test or anything.
兄は優秀だが 力があるゆえに
愛を信じていない。
The eldest excels, but due to his power,
he does not have faith in love.
弟は 出来が悪いが
その心は 愛に満ちている。
The younger one doesn't have the skill,
but overflows with love.
この世界に これから忍宗は
多大なる影響を及ぼすだろう。
Ninshu will come to exert
enormous influence in this world.
忍宗が
間違いのない道を歩むには→
In order for Ninshu to take
the true and proper path…
力と愛 その両方が必要だ。
both power and love are necessary.
I want my sons to grow
during their journeys…
わしは
２人がこの旅で互いに成長し→
忍宗を支え合うように
なってほしいだけだ。
and learn to nurture Ninshu together.
おい いいかげん出てこいよ。
Enough already! Just come out.
気づいてたのか。
お前 もう大丈夫なのか？
You knew I was there?
Are you all right?
ああ このとおりよ。
あんときは ありがとな。
Yeah, as you can see!
Thanks for what you did back then.
気にすんなよ。
それより 何か用か？
Don't mention it.
So, what's up?
お前に助けてもらってから
裏山の小屋に隠れてたんだけど→
After you helped me, I hid out
in a shack on the hill in the back.
ガスカとエダシがさ…。
Then Gasuka and Edashi…
((ガスカ : 大変だぞ。
アシュラが旅に出ることになった。
Big news!
Ashura is leaving on a journey!
(エダシ)なんでも その旅で
忍宗の後継者が決まるんだとよ))
And that journey will determine who
the successor of Ninshu will be.
ってなことを
聞いたもんだから➡
After I heard that, I couldn't sit still.
いてもたっても
いられなくってよ。
俺も一緒に行かせてくれよ。
う～ん。
Take me with you!
お前 母ちゃんの具合悪いんだろ？
But your mom's sick, isn't she?
そっちはもう大丈夫だ。
She's okay now.
薬が効いたみたいでよ
ピンピンしてやがる。
Seems the medicine really worked.
She's back to her lively self.
で お前のことを話したら
ぜひ役に立ってこいってよ。
So I told her about you,
and she said I should go
and help you.
母ちゃん 忍宗嫌いなんだろ？
なんで？
But doesn't your mom hate Ninshu?
So why—?
それとこれとは別だよ。
That and this are two different things.
A man's obligation
comes before hating Ninshu.
忍宗嫌いの前に
人の義理があらぁな。
だけど 俺
しばらく里には戻らないぜ。
But…I won't be coming home
for a while.
えっ そうなの？
What? Really?
きっと兄さんは こんな使命は
簡単にやってのける。
I'm sure Elder Brother will
pass this test with flying colors.
で 俺が戻らなきゃ 父上も
後継者は兄さんに決めるだろ。
And if I don't return, Father will choose
Elder Brother as his successor.
なるほど。 お前らしいな。
I see…
That's so like you.
それじゃ
どこに行くつもりなんだ？
So then, where do you intend to go?
う～ん どうするかな？
What should I do?
Didn't your dad say
でもよ 親父さん
旅先の連中が困ってるから→
there are people struggling
where you're supposed to go?
助けて来いって言ったんだろ？
Wouldn't it be bad if you
didn't go to help them out?
だったら 行かないと
まずいんじゃないのか？
そうか。 そうだな。
Yeah, that's right.
じゃあ 行くだけ行って
また考えるか。
I guess I should just go,
then figure things out later.
おお！ そうしようぜ。
Yeah! Let's do that!
《タイゾウ : にしても…
ずいぶん 遠いな》
Still…
It's awfully far away!
プハーッ！
地図だと
そろそろのはずなんだけど…。
According to the map,
we should be getting close.
やばい… もう 水がねえぞ。
We're in trouble!
We're out of water.
大丈夫だ。
何が大丈夫なんだよ!?
Don't worry.
How can I not?
お前 水の術は使えないんだろ？
You can't do Water Jutsu, can you?
あぁ 俺が使えるのは 風だけ。
だったら！
No. I can only do Wind Jutsu.
Well then…
近いんだ 神樹が。
えっ？
It's near…
The Divine Tree.
Huh?
感じるんだ 俺のチャクラが…。
I can sense it with my chakra.
前に 父上から聞いたことがある。
Father once told me…
忍宗のチャクラは
神樹から得た力だって。
Ninshu Chakra got its power
from the Divine Tree.
おい！
Hey!
どうやら 着いたみたいだ。
Looks like we made it.
(タイゾウ)びっくりだな…。
This is a surprise!
荒野の真ん中に
こんな恵まれた土地があるなんて。
To find a place so fertile right in
the middle of such a barren area.
How could a village
like this be struggling
こんな村に ハゴロモ様が言った
問題なんて あるのか？
like Lord Hagoromo mentioned?
どうした？
What's up?
We're surrounded!
囲まれてる。
えっ!?
What?
おめえたちは 何もんだ!?
Who are you?!
怪しい者じゃない。
旅をしているだけだ。
We're not suspicious characters…
We're just travelers.
最近は
この村を狙う盗賊も多いからな！
We've had a lot of robbers lately
who've been targeting our village.
俺たちは盗賊なんかじゃない。
信じてくれ！
We are not robbers.
Please believe us.
かまわねえ。 やっちまえ！
Never mind. Get 'em!
うわ～！
タイゾウ！ 木の上にいろ。
Taizo, get to the top of the tree!
うわ～！
やめてくれ！
俺は戦う気なんてない。
Stop this!
I have no intention of fighting!
(カンナ)だったら
さっさと村を出ていきな！
Then leave this village now!
きゃあっ！
Hey, are you all right?!
おい！ 大丈夫か!?
触るな！
いいから！
Don't touch me!
It's okay!
今 治してやる。
I'll heal you.
うまくいくと いいけど…。
I just hope it works.
すごい…。
That's amazing!
何の騒ぎじゃ？
長老様。
What's all this ruckus about?
Lord Elder…
すげぇ ご馳走だぜ！
これ 全部 食っていいのか？
What a feast!
We can really eat all of this?
ハハハ！ 遠慮なく 食べてくれ。
先ほどは 村の者が失礼したのう。
Please don't hesitate, eat.
I apologize for
the rudeness earlier.
別に気にしてません。
Don't worry about it.
それより 荒野に
こんな肥沃な土地があるなんて→
I must say it's a shock to see such
a fertile patch in this barren land.
驚きました。
This village is special.
この村は特別なんじゃ。
(アシュラ)特別？
Special?
まぁ 何もないところだが
ゆっくりしていくといい。
Anyways, there's nothing much
to do here…
But please have a relaxing stay.
ふわ～ぁ！ 早いな アシュラ。
You're up early, Ashura.
この村は いいところだな。
水も食いものも おいしいし。
This is a wonderful place.
The food and water taste great,
おまけに お前が助けた娘は
結構なべっぴんだし。
and as luck would have it,
the girl you saved is quite a beauty.
何も問題なんて ないぜ。
There are no issues here.
Yes. But I still feel it…
coming from over there.
う～ん… でも やっぱ
感じるんだよな あそこから。
何を？
Feel what?
チャクラ。
Chakra…
(タイゾウ)あそこに
神樹があるってのか？
And the Divine Tree is there?
たぶんね。
Probably.
おい どこへ行く？
Hey, where are you going?
あの丘に行きたいんだけど。
I'd like to go to that hill.
ダメだ あそこには誰も近づけるな
と長老に言われている。
You can't.
The Lord Elder says
no one is to go near there.
えっ そうなの？
さあ 帰れ！
Oh, really?
Please leave!
いこうぜ アシュラ。
ああ。
Let's go, Ashura.
Yeah.
なんだか感じ悪いな。
Something's suspicious.
やっぱり何かあるのかもしれない。
Maybe there is something, after all.
おっ あんた
昨日のべっぴんさんじゃねえか。
Oh!
You're the beauty from yesterday.
ちょうど よかったぜ。
Perfect timing.
We're planning on
staying a bit in this village…
俺たち しばらく
村に厄介になるからさ。
どっか案内 頼むぜ。
So I'm hoping you can
show us around.
こいつはアシュラで 俺はタイ…。
This is Ashura and I'm Tai—!
私はカンナ お前 医者なのか？
I'm Kanna.
Are you a doctor?
医者ってわけじゃ…。
I'm not really a doctor…
こいつは忍宗使いだからな。
He knows Ninshu.
忍宗？ そうか あれが…。
Ninshu?
Oh, I see. So that's what it was…
それは 病気も治せるのか？
Can you heal illnesses with that too?
病気？
Illness?
ちょっと来てくれ。
Come with me.
ここは？
療養所よ。
Where are we?
A medical clinic.
あなたに
母の病気を治してほしいの。
I want you to cure my mom's illness.
母さん…。
Mom…
ずっと意識がないの。
She's been unconscious
for a long time.
《何だ これ？
何か 強いチャクラを感じる。
What is this?
I sense a strong chakra.
これって もしかして神樹の…》
Could this be from the Divine Tree?
ダメだ 俺の力じゃ
この病気は治せない。
It's no good.
I can't cure this sickness
with my power.
すまない。
そう…。
I'm sorry.
I see…
皆 キミのお母さんと同じなのか？
Are they all like your mother?
ええ。
Yes.
アシュラ ちょっと来いよ。
Ashura, come here.
これって墓だよな？
These are graves, right?
どうにも
辛気臭い場所だと思ったら。
No wonder this place
felt so creepy.
こんなに この病気で
死んでるのか。
This illness caused all these deaths?
そうよ。
That's right.
やっぱり行くしかない。
I have no choice,
I have to go.
お前は！
You're—!
悪いけど 少し寝ててくれ。
I'm sorry, but I'm going to
need you go to sleep.
何をしている？
What are you doing?
えっと 瞳力の印は…。
Umm…
What were the Visual Prowess
signs again?
こっちのほうが手っ取り早いぜ。
This way is much faster.
アハハハ。
洞窟があるぜ。
行ってみよう。
There's a cave here.
Let's check it out!
(タイゾウ)何だ ここ？
What is this place?
(カンナ)この丘が
こんなになってるなんて。
I didn't image it would
be like this inside!
神樹様の言い伝えは
聞いたことがあったけど。
I've heard legends about
the Divine Tree, but…
(タイゾウ)これって…。
This is—!
間違いない これが神樹だ。
There's no doubt…
This is the Divine Tree.
That tree is the ruin of the specter
that almost destroyed our world.
I've been ordered to
do something about it.
The power of the Divine Tree is
indeed making this